Okay, so let's talk about the ITTOs of
procurement management now, right?
The input tools and techniques and outputs
of procurement management.
Now, there are three processes then in
procurement management, right?
So the very first process then is plan
And then we know that
the output is going to
be the procurement management plan, right?
That's the artifact we're trying to
create.
Procurement management plan is documenting
procedures, is documenting how?
So how are we going to get goods and
services from outside of the open?
organization.
Now, once we've determined, you know,
that we're going to outsource the work,
then what's our strategy for that?
So, it's procurement strategy,
right?
What phases are we going to be going
through and so and so forth?
And again, there's all separate videos on
these.
So separate videos on, we're going to be
talking about big documents, statement of
work, source selection criteria,
make or buy.
We have all separate videos on those.
So these would all be the different
outputs.
Now, you can see there's a lot of
considerations to make.
So plan procurement is
determining, basically, should we
be outsourcing the work, or
should we be doing it in-house?
And there's many different considerations,
which, again, we're
going to be talking about.
You know, just a very
high level could be a
cost-benefit analysis
that we might be doing.
It might be cheaper to do
the work, or rather it might
be cheaper to outsource it
than do the work in-house.
Might be based on what resources we have
and so on and so forth.
So again, we're going to cover those in a
separate video.
But these are the considerations to make
to determine.
should we be outsourcing the work.
Collectively, whatever the reason is that
we're deciding to whether or not to
outsource the worker
do it in-house, collectively,
it's known as a make-or-buy analysis.
And so that's one of the tools and
techniques.
Right, we might be doing some market
research to see what vendors are out
there, something called the source
selection analysis, right, which
essentially refers to what kind of vendors
are going to work for us.
Right, so again, we're going to cover
those in a separate video.
So these would be the tools and
techniques.
Remember, again, just as
a high level, right, an output
is some form of artifact
or some form of document.
This is a document or the artifact that we
are creating.
Input is usually some form
of document, with one or two
exceptions, but usually
some form of document, right?
This is the artifact that we are going to
be considering, right?
Going to be reviewing it, we're going to
be considering.
It's a starting point.
And then tool and technique
is some action that you take,
something that you do or
something that you utilize.
Now, that's planning.
In executing, we have conduct procurement.
And conduct procurement basically refers
to reaching out to vendors, discussing the
project with a vendor,
selecting one of those
vendors, finally signing
the contract with the vendor.
So, again, if we look at the output here,
right, if we look at the artifact that
we're creating, so the selected seller,
we've selected one of those vendors.
Then we're going to negotiate the
contract, So negotiation is a tool and
technique, and then we can sign the
contract or sign the agreement.
That's why selected seller and agreement
are two of the major outputs.
We'll be talking about bidders conferences,
so we're reaching out to vendors.
We're discussing the project with a
vendor.
Vendors going to give us
their proposals, which is by
proposal evaluation
technique is one of those inputs.
Reaching out to vendors,
discussing the project with the
vendor, sometimes we might
be using a bidder's conference.
So there's a separate video on all of
these as well, right?
What are some of the considerations to
make?
There's some of the inputs of conduct
procurement, right?
Well, we need to consider the scope,
the requirements, without communication,
we need to communicate with vendors,
right?
What risks are out there?
At the same time, we're
also going to be looking at
the schedule, the requirements,
and so on and so forth.
So all of these are going to be
consideration.
All of these, we're going to be reviewing
in order to basically go out and reach out
to vendors, discuss the project,
get their bids, get their proposals,
select one of them, and then finally sign
the contract.
Now after we've signed
the contract, now we can
control the work that
the vendor is performing.
So this control procurement
then refers to basically
everything, basically
everything up until closing now.
It refers to after the vendor
has signed the contract, now
we can monitor and control
the work that they're doing.
and everything up until closing is
referred to as control procurement, right?
So a closed procurement naturally is
going, one of the outputs, right?
This is the artifact, right?
We've closed it, right?
We've documented that we've closed it,
right?
Or think of, you know, you're doing some
work in your house.
When does the procurement close once
you've given them the final payment?
Right, you've got some vendors doing some
work in your house, some contractors.
As soon as they've done the work, right,
you're satisfied that
the work is finished.
you've given the final
check or, you know, the
final payment, now the
procurement is closed.
And then throughout the project,
what are you doing, right?
You're observing.
You're doing a performance review.
So that's one of the tools.
You're also doing the earned value
analysis.
Earned value is the, are all the formulas.
Are we header schedule, behind schedule,
over budget, under budget?
Right, we're going to
calculate schedule variance
and CPI and SPI and
all of that kind of stuff.
Again, those are all covered in separate
videos.
But in this case, you're going to be
determining your.
vendors are your vendors ahead of schedule
behind schedule what's their performance
level so that's what the earned value
analysis refers to inspection refers to
testing you're going to be testing the
work of the vendor right you're going to
be inspecting the work so you could think
of this as say user acceptance testing so
you would be doing the user acceptance
testing in this case vendors has done the
work for you you're going to test a
product or again you're doing some work in
your house right you're
walking around seeing how
they're progressing you're
inspecting the work, right?
Did they put the right
cabinets and the right
wall, the right colors,
and so and so forth.
So inspection then is another tool.
We'll talk about audit as well.
And then, so audit is basically
independent review.
Any kind of audit is usually an
What happens if there's
a dispute, right, then
you may have a claims
administration procedure.
Then what are some of the inputs then,
right?
Some of the considerations
to make, some of the starting
point for monitoring
controlling the procurement.
So milestones, lessons
learnt, our requirements,
are they meeting our requirements, right?
Some of the risks that you've identified
and so on and so forth.
Right.
So all of these are going to play a part
in, you know, initially, right,
you need to monitor and control the work
that the vendor is doing.
Are they meeting our requirements?
Right.
So really control
procurement is trying to identify
success and failures of
the procurement relationship.
Are they doing the work that they're
supposed to be doing?
Right.
So you're comparing the plan and
comparing, you know, the actual results.
Remember, actual results is workformist
data.
This is monitoring controlling.
So one of the other
outputs is going to be work
form as information,
which is the interpretation.
So then the interpretation
then is comparing the
data, which is actual
results, with our plan.
have they delivered what they're supposed
to have delivered?
This vendor, have they delivered what
they're supposed to have delivered?
Have they finished by the deadline that we
set them?
So that's all work performance
information.
So you're comparing the actual results
with the plan to get the information.
All right, so these are just some of the
ITTOs then.
Again, remember with any
of these ITTOs, you don't
need to know them in
a huge amount of detail.
They only relate to predictive anyway.
they don't relate to agile so this is not
a major right under or rather knowing the
ITTOs all of them is not a major portion
of the exam anymore but you still need to
have a decent understanding of these ITTOs
okay